<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>ELK on ArBlog</title>
    <link>https://arboat.github.io/categories/elk/</link>
    <description>Recent content in ELK on ArBlog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 01 Feb 2021 00:00:01 +0800</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://arboat.github.io/categories/elk/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>项目中用过的aws服务</title>
      <link>https://arboat.github.io/posts/aws-services/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Feb 2021 00:00:01 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://arboat.github.io/posts/aws-services/</guid>
      <description>Compute EC2 Amazon Elastic Compute Cloud (Amazon EC2) is a web service that provides secure, resizable compute capacity in the cloud. It is designed to make web-scale cloud computing easier for developers. Amazon EC2’s simple web service interface allows you to obtain and configure capacity with minimal friction. It provides you with complete control of your computing resources and lets you run on Amazon’s proven computing environment.
ELB Elastic Load Balancing automatically distributes incoming application traffic across multiple targets, such as Amazon EC2 instances, containers, IP addresses, and Lambda functions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>利用kops在AWS上搭建k8s</title>
      <link>https://arboat.github.io/posts/kops/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jul 2020 00:00:01 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://arboat.github.io/posts/kops/</guid>
      <description>利用kops在AWS上搭建k8s 工具 kops k8s 官方免费工具，支持aws， 谷歌云等，目前貌似不是特别支持阿里云,（aws的eks $150/month, 谷歌云，阿里云免费提供。）
dashboard k8s 官方免费工具，配合heapster插件进行监控， 可查看日志，管理部署，容器,服务的编辑和伸缩等。
awscli aws客户端
kubectl k8s客户端
步骤 1.两个常用值设为环境变量 export KOPS_CLUSTER_NAME=test.test.com export KOPS_STATE_STORE=s3://test-kops  2.创建以及启动s3 bucket 2.1 创建s3 aws s3api create-bucket --bucket test-kops --region us-east-1 —create-bucket- configuration LocationConstraint=us-east-1  *Regions outside of us-east-1 require the appropriate LocationConstraint to be specified in order to create the bucket in the desired region *
2.2 启动s3 aws s3api put-bucket-versioning --bucket test-kops --versioning-configuration Status=Enabled  3.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ELK &#43; Filebeats日志系统搭建与配置 爬坑指北</title>
      <link>https://arboat.github.io/posts/elk/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://arboat.github.io/posts/elk/</guid>
      <description>ELK + Filebeats日志系统搭建与配置 爬坑指北 ELK是Elasticsearch, Logstash，Kibana的合称， 在此础上加上Filebeats向ELK发送数据 几个软件最好用同样版本，这里用的是6.4.2
 Filebeats filebeats用来收集日志并发送到设置好的服务器
filebeats 需要root权限才能执行
配置 fields.yml 默认输出到服务器5044端口
#========\ Filebeat inputs =========\ filebeat.inputs: # Each - is an input. Most options can be set at the input level, so # you can use different inputs for various configurations. # Below are the input specific configurations. - type: log # Change to true to enable this input configuration. enabled: true # Paths that should be crawled and fetched.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>